

Kumaresan S

Team Lead - Full Stack Developer

About Me

Full-Stack Developer with 4 years 8 months years of experience specializing in backend technologies such as Node.js, Typescript, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, and MongoDB, out of a total of 9 years and 8 months of overall professional experience. Proven leader in web application development, seeking a challenging role to utilize my skills and contribute to organizational success.

My Contact



kumarbtechguru@gmail.com



+91-97908-31180



Chennai, Tamilnadu

Expertise

- Node.js, Nest.js, Javascript, Typescript,
- MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis
- Rest APIs, JWT, OAuth2, SAML
- · Docker, Typesense
- AWS SQS, SNS, EC2, EBS, Pipe, Event Bridge, Cloud watch, S3, SES

Education Background

• Anna University - B.Tech IT - 2013

Achievements

• Certificate - Manual Testing - 2016

Availability

I am available to join immediately (15 Days) ensuring a seamless transistion

Professional Experience

Epowerx Learning Technologies Pvt. Ltd. | Team Lead Full **Stack Developer**

May 2021 - Present (3 Years 6 Months)

- · Involvement in project coordination, technical guidance, code reviews, and ensuring project goals are met.
- Responsibilities include designing user interactions, developing server-side logic, ensuring cross-platform optimization, and integrating front-end elements into applications.
- Proficient in both front-end and back-end technologies, capable of creating complete web applications.

AUC Ventures Pvt. Ltd. | Senior PHP Developer

Nov 2015 - May 2021 (5 Years 2 Months)

- Designed and integrated RESTful APIs, enabling seamless communication between front-end and back-end systems.
- · Utilized RFID technology to enhance inventory management and streamline daily sales reporting by scanning all items efficiently.
- · Implemented a user-friendly report generation module that allows users to create reports independently.

HCL Technologies Pvt. Ltd. | Data Analyst

Oct 2013 - Oct 2014 (1 Year)

- · Prepared Savings and Spend Reports for management, consolidating global data to support strategic decisions.
- · Managed file uploads to the Web Spend application and resolved technical issues for efficient reporting.